## Björn Blomberg

#### Systems Developer

3 years of experience in system development

#### **Profile**

Björn is a passionate developer with just over 3 years of experience in full-stack software development, both in larger teams and as an individual developer. He has worked and studied in various systems related to web development and cloud services. Previously, he has implemented several end-to-end solutions with APIs and database connections, including further development of Simrishamn Municipality's .NET-based home care system. During his time at SIGMA, he also worked with Azure and its services to develop a transportation system.

Björn has strong problem-solving skills and continuously strives to learn new techniques and tools. His background in software development also includes other technologies and tools such as JavaScript, Vue, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, React.js, MongoDB, Google Cloud, and Git, making him adaptable and capable of working with most technologies.

## Experience

### Nortic, Fortnox importer – 2023/09 to 2024/03

Björn worked on integrating Nortic's own system to enable the export of transactions to Fortnox. During this period, various AWS services were used, such as Lambda functions, to parallelize the workflow using MQTT message queues. Python was extensively used in this project.

Additionally, Björn worked with Google and Apple Wallets to enable the export of tickets from Nortic's own system, allowing users to view them on their phones. Various AWS services and Node.js were also used here.

Technologies used: Java, Node.js, TypeScript, JavaScript, Python, HTML, CSS, GIT, Bash, Linux, and serverless (AWS)

## CGI, Server Manager Client – 2023/08 to 2023/09

Björn was the sole developer for this project, managing various functions of a server ranging from service monitoring to a file retrieval interface. The user interface uses scalable vector graphics to achieve better user-friendliness and aesthetics. Development was implemented following all the steps in a CI/CD process.

Technologies used: Node.js, TypeScript, JavaScript, Vue3, HTML, CSS, GIT, Bash, Linux, and SVG.



### Qualifications

- Networking
- Problem-solving
- Software design
- Agile workflows
- Server maintenance
- Linux system / Bash
- Assembler AT&T/ GNU
- C / C++ / C# / Objekt-C
- Java / JavaScript / .NET
- Python / GO
- HTML / CSS / PHP /SQL
- Spring Boot / Gradle
- Unit Testing
- Integration Testing
- Windows Subsystem Linux (WSL)

#### Tools & Software

- Jira
- Git
- Visual Studio
- Android Studio
- IntelliJ
- Eclipse

#### Languages

Swedish, English

## CGI, Blekingetrafiken Bus App - 2023/08 to 2023/08

Björn was the sole developer where he performed all steps in the process from CI/CD, implementation, testing, to project publication. The project helps Björn and others to check transportation to and from the CGI office for more efficient time management. The app uses Blekingetrafiken's API to retrieve data on various destinations.

Technologies used: Python3, GIT, Bash, Linux, Docker, and Jenkins.

### CGI, Flexmeister – 2023/06 to 2023/08

To more efficiently log and manage employees' flex time, Björn was involved in creating a flex time management app with a web-based client and a server with a Rest API designed to be extensible if more types of clients were needed. Development was implemented following all the steps in a CI/CD process.

Technologies used: Python3, GIT, Bash, Linux, Docker, and Jenkins.

## CGI, Student Project in collaboration with BTH, Software Developer - 2020/02 to 2020/06

Together with his team, Björn developed a drawing management system for the navy. The project used agile workflows with the use of the Jira tool. Development included Java, Spring Boot, Unit Testing, and Integration tests.

Technologies used: Java, JavaScript, Spring Boot, Visual Studio Code, Gradle, Git, Jira, Unit Testing, and Integration tests.

## SIGMA, Web/Software Development - 2019/02 to 2019/07

During this time, Björn, along with his team, developed a transportation system for Karlskrona municipality, which is now used by municipal employees to book transportation. He was a full-stack developer focusing on testing and front-end development.

Technologies used: JavaScript, Dart, NodeJs, Gradle, MariaDB, Azure, Google Cloud, Git, React.js, and Maven, Docker.

## Sjobeck Prime, Server Manager/Software Development - 2014/01 to 2014/08

During his time at Sjobeck Prime, Björn set up Linux-based development servers and developed prototypes for iPhone. He was also responsible for internal servers and services.

Technologies used: Java, Bash, Objekt-C, MySQL, XCode, Linux, Git, and Jira

### Simrishamn Municipality, IT Department - 2011/03 to 2011/09

Björn developed the municipality's reporting system for home care, mostly in the .NET programming language.

Technologies used: MySQL, .NET, JavaScript, Visual Studio, and Git.

# Crunch Fish, APU/ Android app development - 2009/01 to 2010/01

Björn worked on developing a music-focused app for Android. He also contributed to prototyping for future projects.  $\ 2$ 

Technologies used: Java, XML, HTML, and Android Studio.

## Technical Specializations

Frontend development Backend development Linux & DevOps CI/CD

## Education

- Software Engineering, Bachelor's degree, Blekinge Institute of Tech 2017 ongoing
- Technical Preparatory Year, Bachelor's degree, Blekinge Institute o2015 2016
- Java Development (1 year), Vocational Training, Malmö 2014
- Linux System Specialist (2 years), Vocational Training, Helsingborg 2012 2014

Linux system and its structure, virtualization and clustering of systems and services, user management in a Linux environment, web server service management and maintenance.

Competence	Years	Proficiency
Technical knowledge		
C++	6	3
С	2	2
C#	2	2
Objective-C	1	1
Linux	8	4
Bash	8	4
Unit Testing	3	3
Integration Testing	2	2
Load Testing	2	2
Assembler AT&T	3	3
Azure	1	1
Spring Boot	1	2
Java	2	3
JavaScript	3	3
NET	1	1
Python	1	2
GO	1	1
HTML	8	3
CSS	8	2
PHP	1	1
SQL	3	2
Docker	1	2
Chat-GPT	1	2
MongoDB	1	2
PostgreSQL	1	2
Bootstrap	1	2
Jenkins	1	1
Maven	1	1
Gradle	1	1
Windows Subsystem for Linux (WSL1, WSL2)	3	3
Application knowledge		
Eclipse	1	2
Visual Studio	10	3
Android Studio	1	2
IntelliJ	3	3
Git	5	3
IT disciplines		
System Developer	3	3
Software Developer	6	3
Embedded Software Development	1	3
CI/CD Processes	3	3
Agile ITIL Workflows	3	3
Languages		
Swedish	30	4
English	25	4
*Proficionar laval: 1 - Rasia 2 - Interme		

<sup>\*</sup>Proficiency level: 1 = Basic, 2 = Intermediate, 3 = Advanced, 4 = Expert